# RUSLAN PRAKAPCHUK

### PERSONAL INFORMATION

born 18 April 1988

citizenship Belarus

residence Odessa, Ukraine

email fer.obbee@gmail.com

skype ruslan.prokopchuk

github https://github.com/ul

*phone* +380 (50) 676 63 80

#### PROFILE

I prefer to participate in projects having a high positive social impact by either revolutionary innovations or humble improvements of a day-by-day life and work. That's why nowadays I'm specialized in front-end development (Web UIs are an important part of millions of people's access to tech goodness) and why I'm highly interested in Machine Learning (it is one of the frontiers of life's improvements today).

I admire equally two things in programming: it is the source of endless play and it is the tool for getting things done. I like to evaluate new technologies and integrate them into development process when they match my criteria including simplicity (they reduce incidental complexity) and robustness (they don't eat my laundry). That's why nowadays I favour Clojure and ClojureScript stack for the most of my tasks and evaluating OCaml and BuckleScript as the next level up.

# WORK EXPERIENCE

2016–Present Senior Software Engineer, Lohika

Participated in development of 100kLOC SPA with React/Redux stack:

- Reduced app complexity significantly by expressing data dependencies in reactive way.
- Improved unit-testing experience by more fine-grained separation of pure and impure code.
- Implemented tons of new features.

2015–2016 Senior Software Engineer, Condense

Creating single-page applications for managing wide range and volumes of data with complex logic for Australian research institutions. Detailed achievements:

- Developed application architecture based on unidirectional flow and functional reactive programming paradigms.
- Developed ClojureScript libraries implementing that architecture and used them with Facebook React to achieve great development performance and code clarity and maintainability.
- Delivered large applications using mentioned approach and libraries.
- Refactored existing applications to significantly reduce their incidental complexity.

Lohika Odessa, Ukraine Onsite

Condense Hobart, Australia Remote Full-stack Web Developer, A-a-ah!

A-a-ah! Moscow, Russia Remote Project dedicated to cities, their places and events. Mostly focused on Moscow. Back-end & front-end programming. LAMP stack, Yii + Smarty, Redis, Javascript/jQuery, HTML, CSS.

Links:

- Russian version, lot of content, regularly updated
- English version, less actively maintained

2011–2012 Software Engineer, N-COM

N-COM Moscow, Russia Full Brain-Computer Interface software package: signal recognition, filtration, classification, interface to various controlled devices, feedback/training/gamification applications. Technology stack: C#, Python, scikit-learn, MDP, PyQT, ZeroMQ.

2006–2008 Web Developer, European Radio for Belarus

ERB Minks, Belarus Support and further development of radio's website based on Campsite PHP engine. The site was actively used for radio streaming and news publishing. LAMP stack, plus Javascript/jQuery at the front-end part.

#### EDUCATION

2010–2013 University of Effective Development, Kiev

Instructor of Psychotechnics

Studied theoretical foundations and pragmatic techniques of psychic resources utilization, such as attention control and extreme situations handle and recover. Acquired qualification to use and teach those techniques.

2005–2008 Belarusian State University, Minsk

Laser Physics and Spectroscopy 3-year course Was in love with physics, but left university to follow my two other passions: travelling and programming.

## Note

I have no official university diploma. Sorry if it is an issue for you.

# COMPUTER SKILLS

Languages Clojure, ClojureScript, Julia, Python, JavaScript, CoffeeScript, HTML, CSS,

SASS, LESS, OCaml, BuckleScript

IS Frameworks React, Redux, virtual-dom, inferno

IS Build Tools Browserify, Webpack

DBs MySQL, Redis, Datomic

VCS Git, Mercurial

OSes Linux, Mac OS, Windows

Other Functional Programming, API Design, Machine Learning

### OTHER INFORMATION

Languages Russian · Mothertongue

Belarusian · Mothertongue

ENGLISH · Intermediate (conversationally fluent)

Interests

Flutes  $\cdot$  Dorombs  $\cdot$  Modern Jazz  $\cdot$  Computer Music  $\cdot$  Travelling Constructivist epistemology  $\cdot$  Psychotechnics  $\cdot$  Magic: the Gathering

February 14, 2017